Nick Coms

Senior Javascript Developer, Architect & Advocate

SUMMARY

Senior Full-Stack Javascript developer who started developing with Borland Turbo Pascal and later some assembly on an original 4.77Mhz IBM PC some 22 years ago.

I executed my first XMLHttpRequest back in 1999 on 1E5 and was immediately hooked on the freedom and dynamic nature of the language.

In the following years I developed a Single-Page Application framework based on a self-invented XML syntax for defining fully functional, resizeable pixel perfect copies of Windows 7 (Windows XP at first with all 3 color themes, followed by office 2003, and later adopted Vista and the Aero look).

I simply love Javascript and have been using it on front and back-end (Aptana Jaxer followed by Node.js) for well over 15 years and have no doubt that I will keep on using it and the new ECMAScript 6 and 7 features now my favorite language is finally getting the attention, respect and love it deserves.

Research & Development Project

ITEA LASCOT (Large Scale Collaborative Decision Support Technology)

IWT SERKET [SEcuRisation KEeps Threats]

GENESIS FP7 [European Commission FP7 R&D Project]

LANGUAGES

Dutch [Mother Tongue]

English [Fluent]

French [Intermediate]

EDUCATION

RUCA Antwerp [1996 - 1997]

SIHA Antwerp [1994 - 1996]

CONTACT INFORMATION

Markt 19,
2940 Hoevenen (Antwerp), Belgium
(+32) 477 421 888

<u>oomsni@gmail.com</u>

<u>twitter.com/nickooms</u>

<u>linkedin.com/in/oomsnick</u>

github.com/nickooms

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Javascript (JScript, ES3+)
ECMAScript 2016 (ES7)
ECMAScript 2015 (ES6)
C# (.NET Framework 1.0 - 4.6)
VB (6.0 - .NET Framework 2.0)
C (C, C++)
JAVA (JAVA SE 6, JAVA SE7)
PASCAL (TURBO PASCAL)
HTML (HTML4, HTML5, DOM, CANVAS)
CSS (CSS, CSS3, Sass, SCSS)
XML (XSD, XSLT, XQuery, DOM, SOAP)
SQL (ANSI SQL 92 - 2011)
ASM (x86, asm.js, WebAssembly)
GL (OpenGL, WebGL, GLSL)
BPMN 2.0, BPEL

FRAMEWORKS

JQuery, JQuery UI, ExtJS, Bootstrap AngularJS, Angular 2 ReactJS, Flux, Redux, NodeJS, NPM, ExpressJs, KDA

DATABASES

MongoDB, MongooseJS MySQL, GEOSpatial PostgreSQL PostGIS, SQL Server, Oracle PLSQL

OPERATING SYSTEMS

MSDOS, Windows (3.10 – Windows 10) Linux (Debian, Fedora, Android) Mac OS X. iOS

EXPERIENCE

Freelance & Open Source Projects [2015 - 2016]

4C / Cronos [1998 - 2015]

Business Solutions [1997 - 1998]

Solvay NV [1997]

PROJECTS

Freelance & Open Source [2015 - 2016]

ReactJS, AngularJS, ECMAScript 2015, ECMAScript 2016, Webpack, RollupJS, WebGL, WebAudio

AGIV [2012 - 2015]

OpenLayers Node.js Javascript CSS HTML5 XML JSON Jaxer Buddata Studio (JavaScript-based rich web client) Buddata UI Framework (JavaScript codebase used by Buddata Studio) Buddata OGC Web Feature Service 2.0 Enterprise Architect (Sparx) ShapeChange 2.0 Buddata ebXML3.0 Registry Service/OGC CSW for ebRIM Prototype resolver-broker Bizagi Process Modeler, MySQL, Postgresql/PostGIS

ITINERIS [2012]

C#, MS Visual Studio, XSLT, MS Word, SQLServer, Microsoft AX

ARCELOR MITTAL LOGISTICS [2012]

C#, XSLT, SQL SERVER

KZENLABS [2011 - 2012]

Java, C#, Node.js, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, XML, JSDN, Jaxer, Buddata Studio, PostgreSQL/PostGIS MySQL

GENESIS FP7 - 4CT/kZenLabs [2008 - 2011]

JAVA, C#, NDDE.JS, JAVASCRIPT, CSS, HTML5, XML, JSDN, JAXER, BUDDATA STUDIO (JAVASCRIPT-BASED RICH WEB CLIENT), BUDDATA UI FRAMEWORK (JAVASCRIPT CODEBASE USED BY BUDDATA STUDIO), BUDDATA OGC WEB FEATURE SERVICE 2.D, BUDDATA OGC WEB PROCESSING SERVICE, BUDDATA OGC CSW FOR EBRIM, POSTGRESQL/POSTGIS, MYSQL